

# CHARLES VERLEYEN

**Ph.**: +32 497 20 16 60 E-mail: charles.xavier.verleyen@gmail.com GitHub: Charles1104



### **OBJECTIVE**

Data Scientist seeking to work with an international data-oriented company where I will be able to put into practice my mix of soft and hard skills acquired through ten years of education and experience in different countries and sectors.

#### EDUCATION & PROFESSIONAL DEVELOPMENT

•	<b>Bootcamp in Web development</b> – Devleague (Hawaii)	Mar 2017 - Jun 2017
•	<b>Doucanib iii Web acyclobilicht</b> – Devicague (11awaii)	Mai 2017 - Jun 2017

**APICS CPIM (5 modules obtained) Sep 2012** 

Msc in Business engineering - major in Supply Chain Management (cum laude) Sep 2009 - Jun 2012

Louvain School of Management, Belgium and National University of Singapore

**Bsc in Business Engineering** (cum laude) Sep 2006 - Jun 2009 Université Catholique de Louvain, Belgium

# **WORK EXPERIENCE**

**Data Scientist** Aug 2017 - Nov 2017

Data Science Retreat (Berlin, Germany)

**Strategic Sourcing Manager** 

Jul 2015 - Dec 2016

CTA Group (Antwerp, Belgium)

- Management of the chemical consignment contracts for three gold mines in West Africa.
- Developer of Business analytics reports using VBA in Excel

Feb 2015 - Jul 2015 **Project Manager** 

Cimko (Kinshasa, Democratic Republic of Congo)

o Project management coordinator with all the departments, daily reporting to the GM and recruitments.

**Procurement Manager** 

Jan 2014 – Jan 2015

Kempinski Hotel Fleuve Congo (Kinshasa, Democratic Republic of Congo)

o Responsible for all the purchases of the hotel. Manage a team of eight persons.

**Supplier Quality Engineer** 

Dec 2012 - Dec 2013

General Electric (San Luis Potosí, Mexico)

Responsible for the procurement of electronic commodities from 30 suppliers.

# LANGUAGES AND COMPUTER SKILLS

- Human Languages: French (native), English (fluent; 90%), Spanish (fluent; 90%), Dutch (intermediate; 50%)
- Computer Languages: Javascript (intermediate), NodeJS (intermediate), Python (intermediate), SQL (proficient), Sequelize (proficient), PostgreSQL (intermediate), HTML (intermediate) and CSS (intermediate).
- Software Skills: Microsoft office suite (VBA programmer), Microsoft Dynamic Nav 2013 & Jet reports, SAP (modules MM and PP), SAS (Certified Base Programmer for SAS 9), AnyLogic and Adobe suite.

### ADDITIONAL EXPERIENCE AND ACHIEVEMENTS

- Vice President of a renowned Junior Enterprise (LSM Conseil www.lsmconseil.com) from 2008 until 2010.
- **Volunteer in a South African camp** provided care to the animals (summer 2004).
- Sports enthusiast with active participation in Tennis and Swimming; Amateur of Horse Riding.
- Holder of "PADI Open Water Diver Certificate" and "PADI Advanced Open Water Certificate".